MARTIN SUGASTI

📧 martinsugasti@gmail.com | 📞+598 98 704 890 | 📍 Uruguay - Remote

PROFILE

I am an industrial engineer, with experience working in supply chain. However, due to vocational preferences, I decided on a change in my professional profile and started studying Software Engineering and working as a full-stack developer.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering (4th grade) Engineering Faculty, UDELAR 2018 - Present **Graduated in Industrial Engineering** 2009 - 2015 Engineering Faculty, UDELAR First Certificate in English University of Cambridge 2000 - 2008

SKILLS

Ruby On Rails - React - SQL - Scrum

Git - Javascript - Redux - React Router - Heroku - GCP - Stripe - Mailgun - Twilio - Salesforce - Postman - Honeybadger

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

02/2021 - Present Vairix **Full Stack Developer** Montevideo, Uruguay

Since joining the team, I have continued to acquire knowledge in Ruby on Rails and learned other technologies, such as React. I've worked on building robust web applications and seamless user experiences working as a staff augmentation professional for an American company, where I've gained hands-on experience with a wide range of technologies, including SQL, Redux, React Router, GCP and Heroku, have integrated key APIs such as Stripe, Mailgun, Twilio and Salesforce, and have used development tools such as Postman and Honeybadger to ensure quality and reliability.

09/2019 - 02/2021 EagerWorks SRL **Full Stack Developer** Montevideo, Uruguay

Worked as a full-stack developer using Ruby on Rails framework gaining experience in, within others, authentication and authorization systems, background jobs, scheduled tasks, ajax requests, third-party APIs integration, internationalization, mailers, data visualization, etc. Alongside RoR, I also gained experience with other languages, libraries and development tools such as HTML, CSS, JS, bootstrap, git, GitHub, SQL and Heroku. During this time, I have dealt with a variety of clients, spanning from small local companies to large multinational corporations using Agile/Scrum development techniques, staying in touch with clients daily, and reaching mutual agreements on ideas and next steps.

Montevideo Refrescos SRL 04/2017 - 09/2019 **Maintenance Analyst** Montevideo, Uruguay

Planned preventive and corrective maintenance for the Coca-Cola products bottling company in Uruguay.

Executed the maintenance migration in SAP. Approximately 1,800 maintenance plans were redesigned.

Yazaki Uruguay SA 05/2015 - 12/2016 **Production Coordinator** Las Piedras, Uruguay

Supervised production plan on a daily basis, coordinating activities with 3 production supervisors.

• Led a team of 200 plant operators with 4 plant supervisors direct reports and negotiated with labor unions.

Abengoa Teyma SA 11/2012 - 10/2013

Technician Assistant Montevideo, Uruguay

Constructed the electro-mechanical cost-estimate of water purification plant and of concrete/cement plant extension.

LINKS OF INTEREST

LinkedIn 🔗

Simplest Resumes - RoR / React Personal Project 🔗

Urse Seguros - Insurance Broker Website 🔗

Jardín Y Más - E-Commerce Website 🔗

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Barret Leider - Contact upon request **Project Manager** - Ampion

Ignacio Grondona - Contact upon request Technical Leader - Eagerworks SRL

Eng. Jimena Vanoli - Contact upon request

Maintenance Manager - Montevideo Refrescos SRL

Facundo Alcaraz - Contact upon request Full Stack Developer - Vairix SRL

Eng. Santiago Bertinat - Contact upon request **CEO** - Eagerworks SRL

Eng. Agustin Irazoqui - Contact upon request General Manager - Yazaki Uruguay SA